MESIOYE SAMSON

Address: 5, Tunde Abimbola Street, Magodo phase II, Magodo-Lagos. **Email:** jazzygee36@gmail.com **Phone:** 09123202867, 08136668316

Professional Summary

Self-motivated Web and App Developer with 3 years of experience working on multiple projects. Passionate and hardworking with a penchant for meeting deadlines. Interested in roles indulging best practices and offering diverse customer projects.

Skills

- HTML5, CSS/CSS3, Bootstrap4, SASS, Chakra ui, Material ui
- JavaScript,
- Typescript,
- React JS,
- Next JS
- Node JS, Express
- MongoDB
- Git, Github
- Api testing(Postman, REST Client)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Mid React JS Developer

Plagad

Nov 2021 – Nov 2022 Ikeja, Lagos.

Responsibilities:

- Use markup languages like HTML to create user-friendly web pages
- Maintain and improve web applications
- Optimize applications for maximum speed
- Design mobile-based features
- Collaborate with back-end developers and web designers to improve usability
- Get feedback from, and build solutions for, users and customers
- Write functional requirement documents and guides
- Create quality mockups and prototypes
- Help back-end developers with coding and troubleshooting
- Ensure high quality graphic standards and brand consistency
- Stay up-to-date on emerging technologies

- Maintain standards for reliability and performance of production
- Write easy-to-understand user interface text, online help and developer guides
- Create tutorials to help end-users use a variety of applications
- Create and maintain the information architecture
- Produce high-quality documentation that meets applicable standards and is
- appropriate for its intended audience
- Write easy-to-understand user interface text, online help and developer guides
- Create and maintain the information architecture

Junior React JS Developer

Jan 2021- Oct 2021

MIN

Lekki, Lagos.

Responsibilities:

- Worked as Front-end Software Engineer
- Develop high performance customer facing E-commerce using JavaScript, React JS,
 Next JS and Materia ui as the Designed System.
- Used NextJs for server-side rendering for better performance and for SEO.
- Implementing functionalities at the Front-end level using state and useContext.
- Skilled in leading frameworks as React.js to build high-quality, scalable and reusable components and Front-end solution.
- Designed layouts on the front-end and developed web pages responsive for smart phones, tablets and Personal desktops using HTML5, Material UI, React JS.
- Achieved APIs calls from back end NodeJS using React axios.
- Developed an internal application using React JS, Next JS, Express and Node JS for Relationship Mangers.

Junior JavaScript Developer

Apr 2020- Oct 2020

Bedge

Lekki phase II, Lagos.

Responsibilities:

- Creating an interface that is user friendly using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Documented code, so other developers can understand and contribute to it
- Worked in designing, developing and testing the web application by using the HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, and JavaScript.

- Worked in designing the CSS templates for use in all pages on the website working with CSS Background, positioning, text, border, margin, padding, and table.
- Designed layouts on the front-end and developed web pages responsive for smart phones, tablets and Personal desktops using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery.
- Developed Graphics using Paint Shop, Corel draw and Photoshop.
- Worked alongside with a senior developer.

EDUCATION:

❖ Yaba College of Education(YabaTech)
 Course: Computer Science.
 Ż Responsive Web Design Certification
 Ż 2020 - Yaba, Lagos.
 Ż 2022 FreeCodeCamp.

❖ Front End Development Libraries
2022 FreeCodeCamp.

❖ Peter king College of MusicInstrument Major: Saxopone2013 - Oko-Afon, Lagos.2015 - Oko-Afon, Lagos.2016 - Oko-Afon, Lagos.2017 - Oko-Afon, Lagos.2018 - Oko-Afon, Lagos.2019 - Oko